Guide to the Solutions To Environmental and Economic Problems (STEEP) Reports 1974-2001
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Solutions To Environmental and Economic Problems (STEEP) Reports
1974-2001
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Archives 293
Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems (Organization)
1 Linear feet of shelf space 1 box
Initiated in 1975, STEEP (Solutions To Environmental and Economic Problems) is an interdisciplinary research/education program focusing on developing profitable cropping systems technologies for controlling cropland soil erosion and protecting environmental quality. The publications consist primarily of research reports from projects funded by STEEP, but also includes research proposals and work plans.
Initiated in 1975, STEEP (Solutions To Environmental and Economic Problems) is a collaborative project involving scientists and educators from the University of Idaho, Oregon State University, Washington State University, and USDA-Agricultural Research Service, in cooperation with grower organizations and agricultural support industries and agencies. STEEP is an interdisciplinary research/education program focusing on developing profitable cropping systems technologies for controlling cropland soil erosion and protecting environmental quality. (From STEEP’s website. Accessed September 10, 2010)
The publications consist primarily of research reports from projects funded by STEEP, but also includes research proposals and work plans. Items from STEEP's earlier days include papers discussing what directions (priorities) the program should take/fund as it proceeded.
The collection is arranged in a single chronological sequence.
This collection is open and available for research use.
The research proposals and reports of Solution to Environmental and Economic Problems (STEEP) were transferred to Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections at the Washington State University Libraries by Sheila Brooks of WSU's Agricultural Research Center in 2010 as part of a publications file (UA 2010-05). These reports and proposals were separated in 2010.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems (Organisation)
Soil conservation -- Northwest, Pacific.; Conservation tillage -- Northwest, Pacific.; Agricultural conservation -- Northwest, Pacific.; Drainage -- Northwest, Pacific.; Runoff -- Northwest, Pacific.
Agriculture; Washington (State); Oregon; Idaho
- Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: A Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest (STEEP Proposal). March 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Priorities for Erosion-Sedimentation Research in the Pacific Northwest.
- November 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- April 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Status Report of Progress on Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems (STEEP). December 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- STEEP Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest.
- 1977. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Original Proposal March 1974, Work Plan 1976, Progress Report 1976 and Work Plan 1977. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Original Proposal March 1974, Work Plan 1977, Progress Report 1977 and Work Plan 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Status Report of Progress on Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems (STEEP). November 21-22, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- STEEP Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Original Proposal March 1974, Work Plan 1977, Progress Report 1977 and Work Plan 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Preliminary Report, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1978, Work Plans 1979, November 8, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 1978 Annual Report, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1978, Work Plans 1979, November 8, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 1978 Annual Report, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1978, Work Plans 1979, November 8, 1978. USDA SEA-AR Aberdeen, Idaho, SEA-AR Prosser, Washington, SEA-AR Pullman, Washington, SEA-AR Pendleton, Oregon (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 1979 Annual Report, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1979, Work Plans 1980, November 6, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 1980 Annual Report, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1980, Work Plans 1981, January 13-15, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 1981 Annual Report, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1981, Work Plans 1982, January 19-20, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- 1982 Annual Report No. 8, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1982, Work Plans 1983, January 25-26, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- 1983 Annual Report No. 9, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1983, Work Plans 1984, January 17-18, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- 1984 Annual Report No. 10, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1984, Work Plans 1985, January 8-9, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- 1985 Annual Report No. 11, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1985, Work Plans 1986, May 20-21, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- 1986 Annual Report No. 12, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1986, Work Plans 1987, January 6-7, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- 1987 Annual Report No. 13, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1987, Work Plans 1988, January 6-7, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- 1988 Annual Report No. 14, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1988, Work Plans 1989, January 4-5, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- 1989 Annual Report No. 15, STEEP, Solutions to Environmental and Economic Problems: An Erosion Research Proposal for the Pacific Northwest. Progress Reports 1989, Work Plans 1990, January 3-4, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- STEEP 2005 Annual Report. November 17-18, 2005. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- STEEP II, A Tri-State Proposal for Research and Information Delivery Systems for the Pacific Northwest. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- STEEP II, Proposal Summary: A Tri-State Proposal for Research and Information Delivery Systems for the Pacific Northwest. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- 1992 STEEP II Progress Report: Research Extension to Protect Soil and Water Resources in the Pacific Northwest. January 5-6, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- 1993 STEEP II Progress Report: Research Extension to Protect Soil and Water Resources in the Pacific Northwest. January 5-6, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- 1994 STEEP II Progress Report: Research Extension to Protect Soil and Water Resources in the Pacific Northwest. January 4-5, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- A Proposal for Research and Technology Transfer for Profitable and Environmentally Sound Cropping Systems for the Pacific Northwest 1996-2000, STEEP III. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- A Proposal for Research and Technology Transfer for Profitable and Environmentally Sound Cropping Systems for the Pacific Northwest 1996-2000, Executive Summary, STEEP III. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- STEEP III, 1997 Annual Report. January 7-8, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- STEEP III, 1998 Annual Report. January 6-8, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- STEEP III, 2000 Annual Report. January 17-19, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 34)